Guide to the Richard Benson Sewall Papers
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
Richard Benson Sewall papers
1830-1999
MS 1413
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
15.2
(36 boxes)
The papers include correspondence, writings, and research materials of Richard Sewall, author of books and other publications relating to Emily Dickinson.
Sewall, Richard B., 1908-2003
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Gift of Richard Sewall, 1985, and Emily A. McDermott, 2018.
Conditions Governing Access
Student records are restricted until 2060 as established by Yale Corporation regulations http://web.library.yale.edu/mssa/collections/research-use-of-yale-university-archives.
Scope and Contents
The papers include correspondence and research materials relating to Sewall's scholarship of Emily Dickinson, other areas of poetry and English literature, and the family of Augustus Hopkins Strong, Sewall's maternal grandfather. Also includes correspondence between Sewall and colleagues and former students, and lectures given to various organizations on Emily Dickinson and other topics. Includes course material relating to classes taught by Dr. Sewall at Yale University, including a class on tragedy in literature.
Biographical / Historical
Richard Benson Sewall served as an English professor at Yale University for more than 40 years. Sewall taught undergraduate courses on English literature, including a course on tragedy in literature. Sewall was also a scholar of Emily Dickinson; his biography of her, The Life of Emily Dickinson, was published in 1974 and won the United States National Book Award in Biography. Sewall came from a family of Congregational ministers; his grandfather was the Reverend Augustus Hopkins Strong. Sewall retired from Yale in 1976 and died in 2003.
Arrangement
The material is arranged by accession.
American poetry; English literature; Bingham, Millicent Todd, 1880-1968; Dickinson, Emily, 1830-1886; Sewall, Richard B., 1908-2003; Todd, Mabel Loomis, 1856-1932
- Original accession
  - Correspondence, writings, and research materials, 1870-1984 (Box 1)
- Additional materials, 1830-1999; Accession 2018-M-0051
  Scope and Contents
  This accession comprises lecture notes and course materials documenting Sewall's tenure as a Yale University professor of English; writings and research files on Emily Dickinson, the Strong family of Rochester, New York, and other areas relating to Sewall's research interests; and correspondence regarding Sewall's research and work at Yale. Also includes personal materials documenting Sewall's professional life and family history.
  - Correspondence, 1933-1999
    - Adams, William E., 1983–1985 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - Aldridge, Josephine Haskell, 1974 (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - Alegria, Alonso, 1979 (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - Anderson, Charles R., 1961 (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - Arnold, William, 1989 (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - Atkinson, Claudene D., 1978–1989 (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - Atkinson, David, related to the creation of the Byrnes-Sewall Award, 1991–1997 (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - Banks, Helen, 1984 (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - Bell, Robyn, 1995–1996 (Box 1, Folder 9)
    - Benet, Laura, 1974 (Box 1, Folder 10)
    - The Berkshire Eagle, 1977 (Box 1, Folder 11)
    - Birtwistle, Carol, 1994 (Box 1, Folder 12)
    - Brogan, Isabel, 1969 (Box 1, Folder 13)
    - Buckingham, Willis, 1989 (Box 1, Folder 14)
    - Buckley, William F., 1976–1993 (Box 1, Folder 15)
    - Bull, H.W., 1973 (Box 1, Folder 16)
    - Carlisle, Thomas John, 1989–1991 (Box 1, Folder 17)
    - Casaday, James L., 1977 (Box 1, Folder 18)
    - Chaichit, Chanthana, 1994 (Box 1, Folder 19)
    - Clark, C.C., 1971–1972 (Box 1, Folder 20)
    - Clark, Connie, 1990–1996 (Box 1, Folder 21)
    - Clark University, 1933–1934 (Box 1, Folder 22)
    - Coffin, William Slone, 1975–1984 (Box 1, Folder 23)
    - Converse College, 1971–1972 (Box 1, Folder 24)
    - Conversi, Leonard, 1971–1992 (Box 1, Folder 25)
    - Creative Arts Workshop, Mini-Park at Audubon Street Complex, 1976–1983 (Box 2, Folder 1)
    - Daskalapoulou, Aud, 1973 (Box 2, Folder 2)
    - Donaldson, Scott, 1972 (Box 2, Folder 3)
    - Dwight, Richard W., circa 1980s (Box 2, Folder 4)
    - Emily Dickinson Homestead, 1976–1977 (Box 2, Folder 5)
    - Emily Dickinson reading, Yale University, thank you notes, 1984–1993 (Box 2, Folder 6)
    - The Emily Dickinson Society of Washington, 1986–1989 (Box 2, Folder 7)
    - Encyclopedia Britannica, 1969–1978 (Box 2, Folder 8)
    - ESQ Journal, Washington State University, Suzanna Jonas's paper, 1984 (Box 2, Folder 9)
    - The Explicator, Virgina Commonwealth University, 1970 (Box 2, Folder 10)
    - Farr, Judith, 1990–1995 (Box 2, Folder 11)
    - Fisher, David, 1996 (Box 2, Folder 12)
    - Folger Shakespeare Library, 1985–1986 (Box 2, Folder 13)
    - Franklin, Ralph, 1977–1980 (Box 2, Folder 14)
    - Freeman, Margaret H., 1992 (Box 2, Folder 15)
    - Friend, Ruth E., 1978 (Box 2, Folder 16)
    - Frost Fellowship, 1986–1987 (Box 2, Folder 17)
    - Gardner, John, 1990–1991 (Box 2, Folder 18)
    - General, relating to Emily Dickinson, 1975–1984 (Box 2, Folder 19)
    - General, relating to Emily Dickinson, 1975–1984 (Box 3, Folder 1-2)
    - General, relating to Augustus H. Strong book, 1978–1991 (Box 3, Folder 3)
    - General correspondence, circa 1960s-1980s (Box 3, Folder 4)
    - Gilman, Bill, 1973 (Box 3, Folder 5)
    - Goud, Kingdon Jr., 1986 (Box 3, Folder 6)
    - Griswold, Joyce Star, 1994 (Box 3, Folder 7)
    - Gupta, Someshwar, 1974 (Box 3, Folder 8)
    - Hagenbuchle, Roland, 1972–1995 (Box 3, Folder 9)
    - Hallen, Cynthia L., 1996 (Box 3, Folder 10)
    - Harvard University Press, 1974–1994 (Box 4, Folder 1)
    - Heginbotham, Eleanor, 1992 (Box 4, Folder 2)
    - Herbarium Project, 1985–1990 (Box 4, Folder 3)
    - Hickey, Jim, 1996 (Box 4, Folder 4)
    - Higgins, Harold, 1986 (Box 4, Folder 5)
    - The Hill School and the Taft School, 1958–1959 (Box 4, Folder 6)
    - Horan, Elizabeth Rosa, 1995 (Box 4, Folder 7)
    - Hueger, Bette, 1983 (Box 4, Folder 8)
    - Hurrelbrink, Nancy, 1993 (Box 4, Folder 9)
    - Inner-City Student Golf, 1999 (Box 4, Folder 10)
    - Japan visit, 1986–1987 (Box 4, Folder 11)
    - Johns Hopkins, 1986–1987 (Box 4, Folder 12)
    - Judson Press, for Augustus Hopkins Strong biography, 1979–1980 (Box 4, Folder 13)
    - Junker, Connie Heaver, 1981–1985 (Box 4, Folder 14)
    - Kerr, Chester, 1972 (Box 4, Folder 15)
    - Kher, Inder Nath, 1971–1974 (Box 4, Folder 16)
    - Kimbel, Ben, 1978 (Box 4, Folder 17)
    - Langton, Jane, 1982–1983 (Box 4, Folder 18)
    - Lease, Benjamin, 1992–1993 (Box 4, Folder 19)
    - Lefkowitz, Frances, 1988 (Box 4, Folder 20)
    - Leibs, Andrew, 1987 (Box 5, Folder 1)
    - Leyda, Jay, 1955–1984 (Box 5, Folder 2)
    - Lowenberg, Carlton, 1983–1991 (Box 5, Folder 3)
    - Mahl, George, regarding Albert Rothenberg, 1972 (Box 5, Folder 4)
    - Marsh, Fabienne, 1978–1991 (Box 5, Folder 5)
    - Matchett, William H., 1961–1967 (Box 5, Folder 6)
    - McNeil, Helen, 1984 (Box 5, Folder 7)
    - Miller, Arthur, 1990 (Box 5, Folder 8)
    - Miller, Ruth, 1968–1993 (Box 5, Folder 9)
    - Monroe, Russell, 1986 (Box 5, Folder 10)
    - Monteiro, George, 1979 (Box 5, Folder 11)
    - Montgomery, Benilde dissertation, 1980–1988 (Box 5, Folder 12)
    - Moore, Charlotte Dickinson, 1984 (Box 5, Folder 13)
    - Morris, Timothy, 1988–1992 (Box 5, Folder 14)
    - Morros, Cheryl, 1974 (Box 5, Folder 15)
    - Mount Holyoke College, 1980–1981 (Box 5, Folder 16)
    - Mudge, Jean, 1972–1974 (Box 5, Folder 17)
    - Murray, Allie, 1994 (Box 5, Folder 18)
    - New Haven Free Public Library, 1987 (Box 5, Folder 19)
    - Newlin, Margaret, 1975–1977 (Box 5, Folder 20)
    - Oberhaus, Dorothy, 1988–1996 (Box 5, Folder 21)
    - Ogorzaly, Tamara, 1979 (Box 5, Folder 22)
    - Orzeck, Martin, 1989–1996 (Box 5, Folder 23)
    - Ottaway, James H., 1995–1996 (Box 6, Folder 1)
    - Patterson, Rebecca, 1948–1973 (Box 6, Folder 2-3)
    - Patterson, Tom, 1978 (Box 6, Folder 4)
    - Pennsylvania State Press, 1986–1989 (Box 6, Folder 5)
    - Perkinson, Grace, 1983 (Box 6, Folder 6)
    - Phillips, Elizabeth, manuscript evaluation, 1986 (Box 6, Folder 7)
    - The Poetry Society of America, 1982–1983 (Box 6, Folder 8)
    - Prentice-Hall, 1962–1963 (Box 6, Folder 9)
    - Presche, Enid, 1981–1989 (Box 6, Folder 10)
    - Reich, Charles, 1977 (Box 6, Folder 11)
    - Reynolds, Jerry, 1972–1973 (Box 6, Folder 12)
    - Richewell, Adrian E., 1992 (Box 6, Folder 13)
    - Ridington, Candace, 1989–1990 (Box 6, Folder 14)
    - The Riverside Church, 1985–1988 (Box 6, Folder 15)
    - Rubens, Richard L., 1994 (Box 6, Folder 16)
    - Rudd, Eric, 1976 (Box 6, Folder 17)
    - St. Armand, Barton, 1974–1975 (Box 6, Folder 18)
    - Sanzo, Eileen, 1996 (Box 6, Folder 19)
    - Scott, W.T., 1960 (Box 6, Folder 20)
    - Siewa, Patricia, 1972–1996 (Box 6, Folder 21)
    - Shaver, Shelly, 1982–1994 (Box 7, Folder 1)
    - Short, Bryon C., 1991 (Box 7, Folder 2)
    - Short Stories for Study, reused edition, publisher correspondence, 1949–1956 (Box 7, Folder 3)
    - Short Stories for Study, publisher correspondence, 1940–1941 (Box 7, Folder 4)
    - Shurr, William H., 1980–1985 (Box 7, Folder 5)
    - Smith, Emily Strong, 1975–1994 (Box 7, Folder 6)
    - Smith, Louise F., 1982–1983 (Box 7, Folder 7)
    - Stone, John, 1993 (Box 7, Folder 8)
    - Strong-Cuevas, Elizabeth, 1985–1992 (Box 7, Folder 9)
    - Strong family, 1965–1981 (Box 7, Folder 10)
    - Synanon, 1961–1965 (Box 7, Folder 11)
    - Talbot, Norman, circa 1960s (Box 7, Folder 12)
    - Thelen, Hubert J., 1971–1972 (Box 7, Folder 13)
    - The Tragic Form, 1954–1964 (Box 7, Folder 14)
    - Triffet, Terry, 1971 (Box 7, Folder 15)
    - Turner, Clara Newman, questions, 1980–1982 (Box 7, Folder 16)
    - University of Virginia Library, 1974 (Box 7, Folder 17)
    - Urubure, Paula, 1989–1990 (Box 8, Folder 1)
    - Vender, Helen, 1983–1987 (Box 8, Folder 2)
    - Virginia Military Institute, 1976–1978 (Box 8, Folder 3)
    - The Vision of Tragedy, copyright, permissions, 1988-1996 (Box 8, Folder 4)
    - Ward, Theodora, 1956–1972 (Box 8, Folder 5)
    - Waugh, Dorothy, 1971–1987 (Box 8, Folder 6)
    - Weinmann, Robert L., 1972 (Box 8, Folder 7)
    - Weiss, Paul, 1964–1995 (Box 8, Folder 8)
    - Whittemore, Reed, 1992 (Box 8, Folder 9)
    - Whittlesey, Julian, 1991–1992 (Box 8, Folder 10)
    - Winsor, Philip, 1995 (Box 8, Folder 11)
    - Wolff, Cynthia, 1989 (Box 8, Folder 12)
    - Woodbridge School, 1954–1957 (Box 8, Folder 13)
    - Woodston, Sally, 1996 (Box 8, Folder 14)
    - Yankee and Reader's Digest letters, 1977 (Box 8, Folder 15)
    - Zinsser, Charlotte P., 1973 (Box 8, Folder 16)
  - Lectures and courses, 1926-1993
    - Emily Dickinson lectures
      - The Academy of American Poets, 1984–1986 (Box 9, Folder 1)
      - After a Hundred Years, 1986 (Box 9, Folder 2)
      - The Belle of Amherst, Acton Library, 1978 (Box 9, Folder 3)
      - The Chemical Conviction, 1984 (Box 9, Folder 4)
      - The Chemical Conviction: Science and the Poet Emily Dickinson, Amherst College, 1987 (Box 9, Folder 5)
      - "The Dickinson Men", Emily Dickinson House, Amherst, Massachusetts, 1966 (Box 9, Folder 6)
      - Don't Compete, Create, 1960–1986 (Box 9, Folder 7)
      - Emily Dickinson and the Axis of Reality, 1981 (Box 9, Folder 8)
      - Emily Dickinson and the Word, 1976–1986 (Box 9, Folder 9)
      - Emily Dickinson at Play, 1987–1989 (Box 9, Folder 10)
      - Emily Dickinson miscellaneous talks, 1976–1978 (Box 9, Folder 11)
      - Emily Dickinson, Piety of a Pagan, 1982–1984 (Box 9, Folder 12)
      - Emily Dickinson plaque presentation, Amherst, Massachusetts, 1964 (Box 9, Folder 13)
      - Emily Dickinson readings, miscellaneous references, 1982 (Box 9, Folder 14)
      - Emily Dickinson: Science and the Poet, 1987 (Box 9, Folder 15)
      - Emily Dickinson Seminar, University of Massachusetts, 1966–1968 (Box 9, Folder 16)
      - Emily Dickinson Seminar, Yale University, 1974–1980 (Box 9, Folder 17)
      - Emily Dickinson's Perfect Audience: Helen Hunt Jackson, 1989 (Box 10, Folder 1)
      - Emily Dickinson Symposium, University of Massachusetts, 1980 (Box 10, Folder 2)
      - Emily Dickinson, The Village Library, Farmington Connecticut, 1977–1983 (Box 10, Folder 3)
      - Emily Dickinson: Voice of the Past, Jones Library Amherst, Massachusetts, 1978–1980 (Box 10, Folder 4)
      - Emily Dickinson: Writer, Folger Library, 1980 (Box 10, Folder 5)
      - The Heart of Emily Dickinson, The Smithsonian, 1986 (Box 10, Folder 6)
      - Helen Hunt Jackson and Emily Dickinson: A Literary Friendship, 1988 (Box 10, Folder 7)
      - How to Teach Emily Dickinson, circa 1960s (Box 10, Folder 8)
      - In Search of Emily Dickinson, 1983–1985 (Box 10, Folder 9-10)
      - Kirkridge event, 1984–1985 (Box 10, Folder 11)
      - Life and work of Emily Dickinson, 1983 (Box 10, Folder 12)
      - The Life of Emily Dickinson, 1973 (Box 10, Folder 13)
      - The Love Life of Emily Dickinson, Whitney Center, 1986 (Box 10, Folder 14)
      - Lyric Wisdom, 1987 (Box 10, Folder 15)
      - Marblehead High School, 1963 (Box 10, Folder 16)
      - Meriden Public Library, 1978 (Box 10, Folder 17)
      - Millicent Todd Bingham Tribute, 1949–1959 (Box 10, Folder 18)
      - Milton Academy, 1970 (Box 10, Folder 19)
      - The Pilgrimage of Emily Dickinson: Piety of a Pagan, circa 1970s (Box 10, Folder 20)
      - The Pilgrimage of Emily Dickinson, Vermont, 1986 (Box 10, Folder 21)
      - The Poet and the Scientist: Emily Dickinson and Edward Hitchcock, 1984 (Box 10, Folder 22)
      - The Poetry Center, 1984 (Box 10, Folder 23)
      - A Poet's Truth, 1970–1971 (Box 11, Folder 1)
      - Samuel Bowles and his Amherst friends, 1977 (Box 11, Folder 2)
      - The Springfield Wellesley Club, 1977 (Box 11, Folder 3)
      - The Soul Selects Her Own Society, Adelphi University, 1975 (Box 11, Folder 4)
      - Three lectures on Emily Dickinson, University of Michigan, 1987–1988 (Box 11, Folder 5)
      - University of Colorado, women helping women, 1979–1980 (Box 11, Folder 6)
      - Vermont Council on the Humanities and Public Issues, 1982–1986 (Box 11, Folder 7)
      - Virginia Schools, 1969 (Box 11, Folder 8)
      - The Voice of the Poet, 1983 (Box 11, Folder 9)
      - Warren Wilson College, 1979–1988 (Box 11, Folder 10-12)
      - Warren Wilson College, 1990–1993 (Box 12, Folder 1)
      - Washington College, 1978 (Box 12, Folder 2)
      - The Word and the Poet, 1976 (Box 12, Folder 3)
    - General lectures and talks
      - Commencement addresses
        - The Barlow School, 1965 (Box 12, Folder 4)
        - General addresses, 1960–1963 (Box 12, Folder 5)
        - Portsmouth Abbey School, 1972 (Box 12, Folder 6)
        - A Sense of The Ending, Williams College, 1975–1990 (Box 12, Folder 7)
        - Willinston Academy, 1959 (Box 12, Folder 8)
        - Windsor School, 1964–1965 (Box 12, Folder 9)
        - Yale Summer High School, 1965–1967 (Box 12, Folder 10)
      - Lectures
        - Abbott Academy, Andover, Massachusetts, 1968 (Box 12, Folder 11)
        - Amherst College, 1979 (Box 13, Folder 1)
        - Are the Humanities Threatened?, Bryn Mawr Club, 1984 (Box 13, Folder 2)
        - Amity High School, 1979 (Box 13, Folder 3)
        - An Audience Fit for Tragedy, Agnes Scott College, 1962–1963 (Box 13, Folder 4)
        - Avon Old Farms School, 1965 (Box 13, Folder 5)
        - The Bancroft School, 1978 (Box 13, Folder 6)
        - Bangor Theological Semenary, 1981–1983 (Box 13, Folder 7)
        - Bedford Public Schools, 1961–1964 (Box 13, Folder 8)
        - Bright College Years, 1969 (Box 13, Folder 9)
        - Calhoun Course on Poetry, circa 1960s (Box 13, Folder 10)
        - Casina Talk, Christmas Cove, Maine, 1993 (Box 13, Folder 11)
        - Chapel Talks, 1938–1956 (Box 13, Folder 12)
        - Clark Art Institute, 1977 (Box 13, Folder 13)
        - The Crisis in Values, Yale Summer High School, 1967–1968 (Box 13, Folder 14)
        - Coaches Club, 1966 (Box 13, Folder 15)
        - The College English Association, 1976–1978 (Box 13, Folder 16)
        - Comedy, 1961 (Box 13, Folder 17)
        - Congregational Church of Christ, Tryon North Carolina, 1978–1979 (Box 13, Folder 18)
        - Converse College, 1970–1973 (Box 13, Folder 19)
        - Cornell College, 1968–1969 (Box 13, Folder 20)
        - Comedy as Catharsis Seminar, Johns Hopkins University, 1988 (Box 13, Folder 21)
        - Creative Arts Workshop, 1978–1986 (Box 13, Folder 22)
        - Dewitt Hall Talk, 1962 (Box 13, Folder 23)
        - Divinity School, circa 1980s (Box 13, Folder 24)
        - Dwight Hall seminar, 1962–1963 (Box 13, Folder 25)
        - East Carolina College, 1964 (Box 13, Folder 26)
        - Faulkner and the Tragic Tradition, Travelers Insurance, 1961 (Box 14, Folder 1)
        - "A Gallery of Heroes" Yale Class of 1924 luncheon, 1984 (Box 14, Folder 2)
        - General information, 1972–1988 (Box 14, Folder 3)
        - Haverford College, 1961 (Box 14, Folder 4)
        - Hebrew University, 1967 (Box 14, Folder 5)
        - Hopkins School, 1978–1979 (Box 14, Folder 6)
        - Illinois State University, 1964 (Box 14, Folder 7)
        - Is Tragedy Dead?, 1968–1970 (Box 14, Folder 8)
        - Israel Students Association Independence Day celebration, 1968 (Box 14, Folder 9)
        - Lectures to various schools on education, 1954–1959 (Box 14, Folder 10)
        - Naturalism, Modern Language Association, 1947-1966 (Box 14, Folder 11)
        - The Old, Old Sophistnies of June, Silliman Senior Dinner, 1954 (Box 14, Folder 12)
        - Old Saybrook Poetry, 1977–1978 (Box 14, Folder 13)
        - Poetry and the New Criticism, North End Club, circa 1970s (Box 14, Folder 14)
        - Quota Club, Taft Hotel, New Haven, 1964 (Box 14, Folder 15)
        - Religion and Literature Talks, 1954–1960 (Box 14, Folder 16)
        - The Reluctant Reader, 1961–1965 (Box 14, Folder 17)
        - Rhode Island State College, 1944 (Box 14, Folder 18)
        - Russia Club, 1955 (Box 14, Folder 19)
        - Science, Specialization and the Humanities, 1943 (Box 14, Folder 20)
        - The Sea in Literature, The Sea Cloud, 1985 (Box 15, Folder 1)
        - Shakespeare's Tragic Vision, Notre Dame, 1964 (Box 15, Folder 2)
        - Simsbury Library, 1978 (Box 15, Folder 3)
        - South Britain Congregational Church Memorial Society, Southbury Connecticut, 1982 (Box 15, Folder 4)
        - The Spirit of the University committee, circa 1960s (Box 15, Folder 5)
        - Thoughts on the Moratorium, 1969 (Box 15, Folder 6)
        - Union Theological Seminary, 1954–1955 (Box 15, Folder 7)
        - Uses of Humor, 1979–1982 (Box 15, Folder 8)
        - The Uses of Humor from Falstaff to the Marx Brothers, Yale Alumni Dinner, 1980 (Box 15, Folder 9)
        - The Vision of Tragedy, Ohio Wesleyan University, 1960 (Box 15, Folder 10)
        - The Voice of the Poet, Whitman and Frost, Woodbridge Library, 1979 (Box 15, Folder 11)
        - Wallace Stevens, The Shakespeare Club, 1985 (Box 15, Folder 12)
        - Wallingford Public Library, 1978 (Box 15, Folder 13)
        - Wesley Foundation, 1955 (Box 15, Folder 14)
        - Wesleyan University, 1968 (Box 15, Folder 15)
        - Western Connecticut State College, 1968–1970 (Box 15, Folder 16)
        - What Happens in Job, The Hill School, 1970 (Box 15, Folder 17)
        - White S.B., 1977–1982 (Box 15, Folder 18)
        - Why Read Poetry?, Tryon Kids, 1979 (Box 15, Folder 19)
        - Williams College, Mystic Seaport, 1977–1978 (Box 15, Folder 20)
        - Williston Academy, 1963–1964 (Box 15, Folder 21)
        - Wilson College, 1962–1963 (Box 15, Folder 22)
        - Worcestor Massachusetts, Yale Club, 1968 (Box 15, Folder 23)
        - Yale Class Day, 1976 (Box 15, Folder 24)
      - Sermons
        - The Concord Academy Chapel, 1987 (Box 15, Folder 25)
        - St. John's Church, North Guilford, 1983 (Box 16, Folder 1)
        - Union Church, South Bristol, 1973–1985 (Box 16, Folder 2)
        - Williams College, 1958 (Box 16, Folder 3)
    - Coursework
      - English 25, 1975–1976 (Box 16, Folder 4)
      - English 39, 1939–1941 (Box 16, Folder 5)
      - English 61 Tragedy
        - Absalom, 1950–1968 (Box 16, Folder 6)
        - Agamemnon at Aulis, 1968 (Box 16, Folder 7)
        - Albee, Edward, 1969 (Box 16, Folder 8)
        - Alcestis, 1954 (Box 16, Folder 9)
        - Antigone, 1965–1980 (Box 16, Folder 10)
        - Antony and Cleopatra, 1958–1977 (Box 16, Folder 11)
        - The Bacchae, 1955–1980 (Box 16, Folder 12)
        - Ballads, 1947–1977 (Box 16, Folder 13)
        - Beckett, Samuel, 1956–1966 (Box 16, Folder 14)
        - Brecht, Bertolt, circa 1960s (Box 16, Folder 15)
        - The Brothers Karamazov, 1950–1986 (Box 16, Folder 16)
        - Camus, Albert, 1964–1968 (Box 16, Folder 17)
        - Conrad, Joseph, 1951–1970 (Box 17, Folder 1)
        - Crane, Stephen, 1944–1964 (Box 17, Folder 2)
        - Dickens, Charles, circa 1960s (Box 17, Folder 3)
        - Dostoevsky, Fyodor, 1928–1959 (Box 17, Folder 4)
        - Dreiser, Theodore, 1926–1957 (Box 17, Folder 5)
        - Dryden, 1956 (Box 17, Folder 6)
        - Electra, 1953–1963 (Box 17, Folder 7)
        - Eliot, T.S., 1940–1969 (Box 17, Folder 8)
        - Everyman, 1951 (Box 17, Folder 9)
        - Exams, 1949–1977 (Box 17, Folder 10)
        - Existentialism general, 1964–1967 (Box 17, Folder 11)
        - Faulkner, William, 1943–1961 (Box 18, Folder 1)
        - Faustus, 1953–1978 (Box 18, Folder 2)
        - Gatsby, 1958–1986 (Box 18, Folder 3)
        - General, 1949–1970 (Box 18, Folder 4)
        - The Greek Oresteia, 1957–1976 (Box 18, Folder 5)
        - Hamlet, 1944–1980 (Box 18, Folder 6)
        - Hamlet Essays, 1948–1967 (Box 18, Folder 7)
        - Hardy, Thomas, circa 1940s (Box 18, Folder 8)
        - Hawthorne, Nathaniel, 1948–1980 (Box 18, Folder 9-10)
        - Hemingway, Ernest, 1950–1981 (Box 19, Folder 1)
        - Herzog, 1966 (Box 19, Folder 2)
        - Hippolytus, 1975 (Box 19, Folder 3)
        - How the tragedy course got started, 1946–1976 (Box 19, Folder 4)
        - Ibsen, Henrik, 1955–1958 (Box 19, Folder 5)
        - Illizin, Ivan, 1966–1974 (Box 19, Folder 6)
        - Intruders in the Dust, 1950–1985 (Box 19, Folder 7-8)
        - Kafka, Franz, 1953–1977 (Box 19, Folder 9)
        - King Lear, 1950–1980 (Box 19, Folder 10)
        - Koestler and Orwell, 1951–1981 (Box 19, Folder 11)
        - Kyd, Thomas, The Spanish Tragedy, 1969 (Box 19, Folder 12)
        - Lectures, 1965–1977 (Box 19, Folder 13)
        - Light in August, 1948–1970 (Box 20, Folder 1)
        - Macbeth, 1954–1980 (Box 20, Folder 2)
        - Marlowe, 1941 (Box 20, Folder 3)
        - Measure for Measure, 1961 (Box 20, Folder 4)
        - Medea, 1958–1976 (Box 20, Folder 5)
        - Medieval Synthesis, 1942–1977 (Box 20, Folder 6)
        - Melville, Herman, lecture, 1947–1980 (Box 20, Folder 7-8)
        - Middleton, Thomas the Changeling, 1950 (Box 20, Folder 9)
        - Miller, Arthur, 1949–1981 (Box 20, Folder 10)
        - Milton, John, 1955–1969 (Box 20, Folder 11)
        - The Nature of Tragedy, circa 1940s (Box 20, Folder 12)
        - Oedipus, 1956–1977 (Box 20, Folder 13)
        - Oedipus at Colonus, 1950–1956 (Box 20, Folder 14)
        - O'Neill, Eugene, 1957–1989 (Box 21, Folder 1)
        - Othello, 1953–1971 (Box 21, Folder 2)
        - Pasternak, Boris, 1959 (Box 21, Folder 3)
        - Paton, Alan, 1954–1961 (Box 21, Folder 4)
        - Phaedra, 1969–1976 (Box 21, Folder 5)
        - Prometheus, 1969–1977 (Box 21, Folder 6)
        - Rocine, Jean, 1951–1969 (Box 21, Folder 7)
        - Romeo and Juliet, 1961 (Box 21, Folder 8)